Guide to the Isaac Rabinowitz papers, [ca. 1965-1988]
Rabinowitz, Issac papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Isaac Rabinowitz papers, [ca. 1965-1988]
14-30-3937
Isaac Rabinowitz 1909-
12.5 cubic feet.
Correspondence, printed material, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence and subject files relating to his career and to the Department of Near Eastern Studies at Cornell.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Near Eastern Studies. Isaac Rabinowitz joined the Cornell faculty in 1957 and retired as Professor of Biblical and Hebrew Studies in 1975. He served as chairman of the Department of Semitic Languages and Literatures, now the Department of Near Eastern Studies, when it was re-established in 1966. Among his major scholarly contributions was the first translation and critical evaluation in modern language of a 15th century Hebrew treatise on the art of Classical rhetoric and its use in interpreting the Hebrew Bible. He was born in Brooklyn, graduated from the University of California at Berkeley and received his Ph.D. from Yale in 1932. He directed B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundations at the University of Michigan, the University of Pennsylvania, and Brooklyn College and served as executive director of the East New York Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Associations in Brooklyn from 1946 to 1955. He came to Cornell from Wayne State University in Detroit where he directed the Program of Hebrew Studies. Isaac Rabinowtiz died on September 11, 1988.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence and subject files relating to his career and to the Department of Near Eastern Studies at Cornell.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Rabinowitz, Isaac,1909-; Cornell University.Dept. of Near Eastern Studies.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Research of parts of the collection designated by the donor requires written permission of the donor. Cornell will forward contact information and requests to the donor.
Donor retains copyright during his lifetime.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical Information
Box 1
Series II. Correspondence
Box 1-5
Personal correspondence (arranged by last name)
Cornell University correspondence and material
Correspondence with Students
Correspondence with Other Institutions
Miscellany
Series III. Research, Papers, Articles, and Books Arranged Topically
Box 5-9
Dead Sea Scroll
Ben Sira
Sardis Synagogue
Parahyba/Phoenician Hoax
A Witness Forever
Judah Messer Leon
David Messer Leon (Son of Judah Messer Leon)
Sepher Hayyashar
On Being Jewish
Pesher/Pesher Nahum
"The Theory of Biblical Hebrew Literature: Prolegomena to a Valid Literary Criticism of the Hebrew Bible"
"How Ancient Israel Perceived Literature: towards A Culturally Valid Understanding of the Hebrew Bible"
"'Āz Followed by Imperfect Verb-Form: A Redactional Device in Biblical Hebrew"
Other Notes (in Alphabetical Order)
Other Articles (in Alphabetical Order)
Series IV. Offprints of Articles and Writings by Isaac Rabinowitz
Box 9
Series V. Courses, Offered Mainly by Isaac Rabinowitz
Box 9
Series VI. Speeches and Lectures
Box 9-10
Series VII. Scholarly or Critical Reviews by Isaac Rabinowitz
Box 10
Series VIII. Collection of Journals and Articles
Box 10-11
Series IX. Reactions, Criticisms, and Reports
Box 11
Series X. Book Collections and Purchases
Box 11
Series XI. Travels
Box 11
Series XII. Bound Manuscripts from Rabinowitz collection #4661
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical Information
  - Appointment Forms and Correspondence with Cornell University, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Background, etc., 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Copy of Curriculum Vitae, List of Publications (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Research Account, 1980-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Vitae--Document #1. Photographs (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Photographs
  - Letters of Recommendation. Curriculum Vitae. Records, 1942-1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Tax Information, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - TIAA/CREF, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Matierial and correspondence about reitirement. TIAA stands for Teacher Insurance and Annuity Association. CREF stands for College Retirement Equities Fund.
  - Transcript at Yale (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Also contains some newspaper clippings and correspondence with Yale
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Personal correspondence(arranged by surname)
    - Alvin H. Bernstein, Acting Chairman, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - David Birnbach, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Chana Bloch/Florie Faerstein (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Also contains correspondence with N.A.Berkoff
    - Chana Faerstein Bloch (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Ross Brann (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Stuart M. Brown (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - J. Brussel-N.Y.-Books, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - T.A.Burkill (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Harry Caplan (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dale R. Corson (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Mrs. Dorothy Bungert's letters re: the visions of her daughter (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Robert Eisenman, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Victor Eppstein, 1959-1970 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Ronald and Deborah Freedman, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Yehoshua Gitay (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - David Halperin (Advisee) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Robert Hoberman, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - William Horowitz (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Alfred Ivry (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Noah Jacobs, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Mr. John T. Johnson, Dr. Mildred S. Johnson-Correspondence on pronunciation of Hebrew in connection with Mrs. Johnson's work as a teacher of Kabbalah, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Prof. Alfred E. Kahn, Dean of Arts and Sciences, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Prof. Alfred E. Kahn, Dean of Arts and Sciences
    - Acting Chairman Prof. Michael Kammen, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      Department of Semitic Languages and Literatures, Cornell University
    - Edward Kiev (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Abraham D. Krikorian (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Jon Lavine (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Samuel Lemberg and Maurice Hexter (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Julius Leventhal, 1959-1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dean Prof. Harry Levin (Cornell University), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Cornell University
    - Norman Malcolm, 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      Also contains two offprints of articles by Norman Malcolm
    - Howard Marblestone, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dan Moore, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - James J. Murphy: Rhetoric, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Prof. Benzion Netanyahu, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Madeline Noveck, 1966-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      Includes exhibition catalogs (co-)authored by Madeline Noveck.
    - Eugene G. O'Neill, Jr, 1938-ca. 1946 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Prof. David Owen, Chairman, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Prof. David Powers, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Jack Sasson, 1977-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Miriam Scheraga, 1967-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Michael Schub, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      Also contains offprints by Michael Schub
    - Edgar E. Siskin, 1964-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Abram Spiro, 1956-1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - F. C. Steward, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Lewis R. Sutin, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Lewis R. Sutin, 1983-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - John Tepfer, 1956-1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Luitpold Wallach, 1962-1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Hayden V. White, 1957-1983 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Paul Winter, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Donald Yates, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Anthony D. York, 1968-1977 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Anthony D. York-Admission to Candidacy Exam [passed] Status of Advancement to Degree, August 11-12, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Georg K. Zucker-Sephardic Studies, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Personal Letters, 1938-1955 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Personal Correspondence, 1956-1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      Mostly from 1957 re Cornell appointment
    - Personal, 1957-1985 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Chiefly from late 1950s-early 1960s
    - Personal, 1962-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Personal, 1964-1986 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Scholars' Correspondence-General-re offprints, etc, 1972-1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous--Letters, 1978- (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cornell University correspondence and material
    - Bib. Literature Book, Funding, etc., 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Proposed Department Procedures (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Graduate Field of Semitic Studies: Specific Requirements (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Semitics: Graduate Field, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Graduate Program-Semitics, Copy for detailed requirements + potential brochure, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Department of Semitic Languages and Literatures, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Contains proposal for the establishment of the department, appointment letter for the chair
    - Department of Semitics, 1972-1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      Department of Semitic Languages and Literatures
    - Candidacies in Semitics, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Department meetings (Box 3, Folder 14)
      (Department of Semitic Languages and Literatures)
    - Department Business, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Department Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous-Department (Isaac Rabinowitz) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence re Cornell Professorship, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence re Cornell Appointment as Professor of Biblical and Hebrew Studies, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Cornell University Library, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Cornell University Library, 1979-1987 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Cornell University Library, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Faculty Forum: "Memoranda for a Preface to the Scriptures", June, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Archaeology Department, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Society for the Humanities (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Hull Memorial Fund (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Cornell University Press, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Correspondence regarding "Book of the Honeycomb's Flow"
    - Printing of Nofet Sufim: Samples,etc. Glossary, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Correspondence about "Book of the Honeycomb's Flow" with Cornell University Press
    - Arts and Sciences: Faculty (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Phi Beta Kappa Society; Ad hoc committee on faculty tenure
    - Phi Beta Kappa, 1966-1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Subcommittee on Instruction in Religion in the College of Arts and Sciences, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Includes correspondence with Dean of Arts and Sciences Francis E. Mineka and Chairman Stuart M. Brown Jr
    - Committee on Chair in Christian Thought, 1959-1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Sabbatic Term: Jerusalem (Israel), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Sabbatic Leave, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Jewish Studies: Campaign, etc., 1988 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Graduate School, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Election to the General Committee of the Graduate School in Cornell University
    - Contracts with University, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      About Professor Rabinowitz's retirement
    - Jehovah's Witnesses' Use of Cornell's Name to "Prove" Superior Accuracy of Their Bible Translation (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Promotion Procedures; chair for Department of Semitics, 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Literary Format Pamphlet, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - University Faculty, 1977-1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Memorial Statements Cornell University Faculty
    - Candidates, 1965-1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Students
    - Talmudic Aramaic, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Charles Branch, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Malti, Fedwa (Advisee-Major); Student File, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Zvia Greenspan, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Copies of Targum on Ezek. 1:1
    - Rev. Richard T. Loring-Candidate Th. D.-General Theological Seminary/I.R.-Examiner, May 3, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Danial Tooker-Advisee, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Lawrence H. Schwartz, Advisee, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Applications: Dannhauser, Shoshana Zaltzman (Semitic Studies), 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Letters re Students, 1958-1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Letters-Students, 1972-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Other Institutions
    - American Oriental Society, 187th Meeting, April, 26-27, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence re COI Memos/OSS, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      (Office of Strategic Services, Washington, D.C.)
    - Correspondence re Completed Papers, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence re "Demetrius" Paper, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Department of Modern Language, University of Northern Iowa. Scholarly Meetings and Conferences-Opportunities for Graduate Students, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - East New York, 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - East New York, 1962-1970 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - East New York Materials, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Fellowship, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Guggenheim, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
    - Guggenheim, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Hillel (Box 4, Folder 25)
      B'nai B'rith Hillel Foundation: Hillel publications
    - Hillel, 1959-1968 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Indiana University, October 25, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - In Jewish Bookland, 1959-1971 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Intercollege Committee on Archaeology, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - MAARAV, 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      (subtitle: A Journal for the Study of the Northwest Semitic Languages and Literatures)
    - National Endowment for Humanities-Edgar Rosenberg, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities: Application, 1978-1984 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Fellowship: Report, Application, etc., 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Evaluations: National Endowment for the Humanities, 1971-1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Report, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities General Correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - National Foundation for Jewish Culture, 1961-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - National Foundation for Jewish Culture Advisory Council, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - New Literary History, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      (subtitle: A Journal of Theory and Interpretation)
    - Prentice Hall, Inc., 1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Letters to Prospective Publishers, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Sardis-Correspondence (Box 5, Folder 10)
      Sardis Expedition, Harvard University
    - Correspondence-Scholarship, 1956-1969 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Social Sciences and Humanities (Research Council of Canada) [Restrict], 1956-1969 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      Request for Review of Research Grant Proposal on "Hebrew Humanism in Italy"
    - Society of Biblical Literature, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Society of Biblical Literature and Exegesis, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      Meeting Schedule and Records
    - Correspondence re Wayne University, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - YMHA and Federation Papers, 1955-1962 (Box 5, Folder 16)
      East New York Young Men's and Young Women's Hebrew Association; Y Review (publication of the East New York Y.M. and Y. W. H. A.)
    - Near East, Bibliography Correspondence with Ettinghausen, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Miscellany, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Miscellany
    - Business/Current/Galveston, 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Business Correspondence, 1958-1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Sundry Materials, 1975-1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Current/In Process/Scholarly and Personal, 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      Includes correspondence with Devon Smith, R.J.Kaufmann, Harry Levin, Matin W. Sampson, and others
    - Towards a Valid Theory of Biblical Hebrew Literature-Reprint Details Correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Replies to Queries Addressed to Cornell and Referred, 1959-1977 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Letter Box 1, from A to H, 1933-1936 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Letter Box 1, from H to N, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Letter Box 1, from H to N, 1935-1937 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Letter Box 2, from A to C, 1931-1938 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Letter Box 2, from D to H, 1931-1938 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Letter Box 2, from I to O, 1934-1938 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Letter Box 2, from P to Z, 1935-1938 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Copies of Isaac Rabinowitz's correspondence from his son, 1, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Copies of Isaac Rabinowitz's correspondence from his son, 2, 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Series III. Research, Papers, Articles and Books Arranged by Subject
  - Dead Sea Scrolls
    - Dead Sea Scroll Paper by Isaac Rabinowitz (Box 5, Folder 34)
      Includes email correspondence with Scott B. Noegel and some offprints
    - Dead Sea Scrolls: Preparation Material for a Book Collection for Prof. Rabinowitz's Articles, and an Introductory Essay (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Various offprints on Dead Sea Scrolls (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Internal Evidence for the Sequence and Dating of Dead Sea Scrolls, 1951-1954 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ben Sira
    - Prologue to Ben Sira (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "The Qumran Hebrew Original of Ben Sira's Concluding Acrostic on Wisdom" (typescript), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "The Qumran Hebrew Original of Ben Sira's Concluding Acrostic on Wisdom"-Hebrew Union College Annual, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Ben Sira, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Includes offprints and notes
  - Sardis Synagogue
    - "An Interim Bibliography of Sardis," by G. Haufmann, R.S. Thomas, and J.S. Waldbaum (typescript), 1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sardis Synagogue (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Materials and reprints
    - "Sardis Synagogue Inscriptions," paper by Isaac Rabinowitz (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Sardis Synagogue Inscriptions (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Materials
    - Sardis Inscriptions-Photographs (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Sardis Inscriptions-Notes, etc. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Sepharad/Sardis" (Box 6, Folder 11-1)
    - "A Preliminary Bibliography of Sardis" by George M.A. Hanfmann (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Parahyba/Phoenician Hoaxes
    - Phoenician Hoax, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Correspondence with Cornell and newspaper clipping from the Boston Globe
    - Parahyba Hoax, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Correspondence with Cornell, New York Times, and Yale University Library
    - Parahyba Hoax (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - A Witness Forever
    - A Witness Forever, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Correspondence with prospective publishers
    - Witness Forever Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Materials relevant to A Witness Forever, 1969-1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      Contains correspondence, related materials, and note
    - A Witness Forever: Original Text Edited By JBR and Reviewed by Isaac Rabinowitz (galley) (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Judah Messer Leon
    - "Sepher Nopheth Suphim: the Book of the Honeycomb's Flow" Composed by Rabbi Judah Messer Leon, Edited and Translated by Isaac Rabinowitz, 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Sepher Nopheth Suphim: the Book of the Honeycomb's Flow" Composed by Rabbi Judah Messer Leon, Edited and Translated by Isaac Rabinowitz, 2 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Translation Manuscript of "Sepher Nopheth Suphim: the Book of the Honeycomb's Flow", Part 1 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Translation Manuscript of "Sepher Nopheth Suphim: the Book of the Honeycomb's Flow", Part 2 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Translation Copy with Corrections of "Sepher Nopheth Suphim: the Book of the Honeycomb's Flow" (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Introduction to Nopheth Suphim (Box 6, Folder 25)
      Notes
    - Notes on Texts relative to Nopheth Suphim (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Nopheth Suphim: Return of Roth; Copy of C (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Translation of Nopheth Suphim: Notes, Bibliography, etc. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Nopheth Suphim: Business letter, etc, 1962-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Nopheth Suphim: Hotsaah: Plan of Work, 1960-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Correspondence about funding, Nopheth Suphim's manuscript, and the progress of translation
    - Letters re work on Nopheth Suphim, 1959-1966 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letter outlining plan of publication of Nopheth Suphim; Preface, 1962-1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Harry Caplan's Nopheth Suphim Emendation (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Page 186-413. HC likely refers to Harry Caplan
    - Harry Caplan's Nopheth Suphim Emendation (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Page 414-477
    - Harry Caplan's Nopheth Suphim Emendation (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Page 478-643
    - Harry Caplan's Nopheth Suphim Emendation (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Page 644-709
    - Photocopy of Nophet Suphim (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Reprints of Papers on/by Judah Messer Leon (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Munich and Parma Mss of Nopheth Suphim (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - IV. The Nopheth Suphim Itself (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - References to Judah Messer Leon (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Messer Leon's Works-beginning with David Messer Leon's Letter (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - David Messer Leon (Son of Judah Messer Leon)
    - Reprints: David Messer Leon (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Material on Rabbi David Messer Leon (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Photograph of Rabbi David Messer Leon (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Sepher Hayyashar
    - the Nature and Function of Sepher Hayyashar (Paper and Lecture), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Sepher Hayyshar Notes (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Sepher Hayyshar (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - "On Being Jewish"
    - On Being Jewish (Box 7, Folder 22)
      Notes and Newspaper Clippings
    - Materials: On Being Jewish (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Pesher/Pesher Nahum
    - Pesher Nahum (Box 7, Folder 24)
      Notes and Materials
    - "Demetrius"-Passage of Nahum-Pesher (Box 7, Folder 25)
      Contains correspondence and two copies of 'the Meaning of the Key ("Demetrius")-Passage of the Qumran Nahum-Pesher"
    - Pesher (Box 7, Folder 26)
      Notes, correspondence, and offprint "The Pesher of Dreams and Scriptures"
    - Pesher, etc. (R. de Q.), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      Includes manuscripts of "Pēsher/pittārōn: Its Biblical Meaning and its Significance in the Qumran Literature"
    - Pesher and Pesher texts of Qumran (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - "The Theory of Biblical Hebrew Literature: Prolegomena to a Valid Literary Criticism of the Hebrew Bible"
    - Introductory: Foreword, Preface, Outlines (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - II: "Word", "Name" in the culture of ancient Israel-nature and process in the Culture of Ancient Israel (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - III: "Writing"-Occasions and Motives for Writing-Function of Literary Recording-Connection with Word (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - IV: Statement of Theory (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - V: the Meaning of the "Bible" to Those Who First Wrote and Used It (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - VI: Historical Sketch of the Production and Compilation of the O.T.-Redaktionsgeschichte (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - VIII: Conflate Nature of the Text of the O.T. (pre-versions) (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - IX: Canon-Meaning of Scripture for Jews and Christians-History of Later Interpretation (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - How Ancient Israel Perceived Literature: towards A Culturally Valid Understanding of the Hebrew Bible
    - Copy of "How Ancient Israel Perceived Literature: towards A Culturally Valid Understanding of the Hebrew Bible" with notations, 1 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Copy of "How Ancient Israel Perceived Literature: towards A Culturally Valid Understanding of the Hebrew Bible" with notations, 2 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - 'Āz Followed by Imperfect Verb-Form: A Redactional Device in Biblical Hebrew
    - 'Āz Followed by Imperfect Verb-Form: A Redactional Device in Biblical Hebrew, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 39)